<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<CALENDAR xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="calendar.xsd">
    <FACULTY name="faculty-of-arts" faculty="arts">
        <TITLE>Faculty of Arts</TITLE>
        <DEPARTMENT>
            <PROGRAMS>
                <PROGRAM name="ACAD" credential="Minor in Acadian Studies" prog-type="MIN" faculty="ARTS">
                    <TITLE>Acadian Studies</TITLE>
                    <P>http://upei.ca/programsandcourses/acadian-studies</P>
                    <P>Co-ordinator</P>
                    <P>Carlo Lavoie (Modern Languages)</P>
                    <P>The Minor in Acadian Studies aims to provide a better understanding of the place and importance of the
                        French language and the Acadian community on Prince Edward Island and in Maritime Canada. The program
                        consists of an immersion in general cultural subject areas and of an analysis of specific literary and
                        cultural topics. The study of Acadian culture may pave the way to graduate school and/or education
                        programs or simply be complement to one’s University study. On the one hand, UPEI’s Minor in Acadian
                        Studies offers students the opportunity to develop both their analytical and the practical skills in
                        French and will provide its students with the foundational skills with which they can pursue their
                        interest in the practice of French. On the other hand, the Minor in Acadian Studies aims to link in a
                        common thematic different courses offered in English which propose a reflection on the Acadian as part of
                        a cultural and linguistic minority.</P>
                    <REQUIREMENTS><REQUIREMENT>
                            <TITLE>REQUIREMENTS FOR A MINOR IN ACADIAN STUDIES</TITLE>
                            <P>A Minor in Acadian Studies consists of <COURSE-REQT name="minor" credits="21">twenty-one
                                    (21) semester hours of credit taken from the list of approved courses</COURSE-REQT>.
                                    <COURSE-REQT name="language-req">The language requirements are <COURSE ref="FREN-241">French
                                        241</COURSE> and <COURSE ref="FREN-242">French 242</COURSE> (both courses could be counted
                                    in the Minor in Acadian Studies if they are not counted for the Major in
                                French)</COURSE-REQT>. <COURSE-REQT name="acad-compulsory"><COURSE ref="ACAD-201">Acadian Studies
                                        201</COURSE> plus three courses among <COURSE ref="ACAD-491">Acadian Studies
                                        491</COURSE>/<COURSE ref="ACAD-491">492</COURSE>, <COURSE ref="ACAD-209">Special Topics
                                        209</COURSE>, <COURSE ref="ACAD-309">309</COURSE>, and <COURSE ref="ACAD-409"
                                    >409</COURSE>, and <COURSE ref="FREN-443">French 443</COURSE>/<COURSE ref="FREN-444"
                                        >444</COURSE>, are compulsory for the Minor</COURSE-REQT>. Prospective students should
                                note, however, that <COURSE ref="ACAD-491">Acadian Studies 491</COURSE> and <COURSE ref="ACAD-492"
                                    >492</COURSE> require students to make a significant contribution to the study of Acadie which
                                will be approved by the Instructor. One of these four courses will, typically, be only offered in
                                the Winter Term of the academic year. In addition, students must select three elective courses.
                                Students using any of the approved courses to complete the Minor in Acadian Studies may not use
                                them to complete a Major or another Minor.</P>
                            <COURSE-REQT>REQUIREMENTS IN FRENCH <COURSE ref="FREN-241">241 FRENCH</COURSE> (See French 241)
                                    <COURSE ref="FREN-241">242 FRENCH</COURSE> (See French 242) </COURSE-REQT>
                        </REQUIREMENT>
                    </REQUIREMENTS>
                    <TITLE>ACADIAN STUDIES CORE COURSES</TITLE>
                    <COURSE name="ACAD-201"><TITLE>201 INTRODUCTION TO ACADIAN STUDIES</TITLE> This course is designed to provide
                        an opportunity to examine the development of Acadian culture through the oral tradition, songs and folk
                        tales. The themes of colonialism, regionalism, folklore and oral traditions will provide the basis for
                        this examination. The object of the course is to develop an awareness of the complex patterns of
                        development in Acadian culture from the French period to the present. The course will consist of seminars
                        and lectures conducted in French.</COURSE>
                    <REQUIREMENT>PREREQUISITES: <COURSE ref="FREN-241">French 241</COURSE> and <COURSE ref="FREN-242">French
                            242</COURSE> or the <EXT-REQT name="permission">permission of the Coordinator of Acadian
                            Studies</EXT-REQT>. <P>Three hours a week.</P></REQUIREMENT>
                    <COURSE name="ACAD-209"><TITLE>209 SPECIAL TOPICS</TITLE> Creation of a course code for special topics offered
                        by Acadian Studies at the 200 level.</COURSE>
                    <COURSE name="ACAD-309"><TITLE>309 SPECIAL TOPICS</TITLE> Creation of a course code for special topics offered
                        by Acadian Studies at the 300 level.</COURSE>
                    <COURSE name="ACAD-409"><TITLE>409 SPECIAL TOPICS</TITLE> Creation of a course code for special topics offered
                        by Acadian Studies at the 400 level.</COURSE>
                    <COURSE-EQUIV ref="FREN-443" course="ACAD-443"><TITLE>443 CULTURE ET LITTÉRATURE ACADIENNES I </TITLE>(See
                            <COURSE ref="FREN-443">French 443</COURSE>) </COURSE-EQUIV>
                    <COURSE-EQUIV ref="FREN-444" course="ACAD-444"><TITLE>444 CULTURE ET LITTÉRATURE ACADIENNES
                        II</TITLE></COURSE-EQUIV> (See <COURSE ref="FREN-444">French 444</COURSE>) <COURSE
                        name="ACAD-491|ACAD-492"><TITLE>491/492 DIRECTED STUDIES</TITLE> The purpose of the course is to provide
                        an opportunity for intensive interdisciplinary research in an area to be determined by the student and the
                        coordinator of the program. Readings and research on the course will be supervised and the student is
                        expected to present the results of the research in the form of an extended essay. This is a tutorial and
                        seminar course. </COURSE> PREREQUISITE: <REQUIREMENT><COURSE-REQT name="ACAD-201">Acadian Studies
                            201</COURSE-REQT> or the <EXT-REQT name="permission">permission of the Coordinator of Acadian
                            Studies.</EXT-REQT>
                        <P>Three hours a week (See Academic Regulation 9 for Regulations Governing Directed Studies)</P>
                        <P><TITLE>ELECTIVES Note</TITLE>: Students who are enrolled in the Major in French and the Minor in
                            Acadian Studies can take at least two electives outside the Department of Modern Languages.</P>
                    </REQUIREMENT>
                    <COURSE ref="CANA-301">CANADIAN STUDIES 301</COURSE>/<COURSE ref="CANA-302">302</COURSE>
                    <TITLE>The Canadian Experience</TITLE>
                    <COURSE ref="EDUC-213">EDUCATION 213 <TITLE>Introduction à l’éducation en français au Canada</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="ENGL-331"><TITLE>ENGLISH 331 The Literature of Atlantic Canada</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="HIST-231|HIST-232"><TITLE>HISTORY 231/232 The Atlantic Region</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="HIST-424"><TITLE>HISTORY 424 History of Canadian Nationalism and the Canadian
                        Identity</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="MODE-252"><TITLE>MODERN LANGUAGES (French) 252 Le français des affaires</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="MODE-339"><TITLE>MODERN LANGUAGES 339 Théâtre canadien-français</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="SOCI-312"><TITLE>SOCIOLOGY &amp; ANTHROPOLOGY 312 Rural Society in Canada</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="SOCI-431"><TITLE>SOCIOLOGY &amp; ANTHROPOLOGY 431 Minority/Ethnic Groups and Canadian
                            Multiculturalism</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <COURSE ref="WOME-311"><TITLE>WOMEN STUDIES 311 Identity and Popular Culture</TITLE></COURSE>
                    <P><TITLE>DIRECTED STUDIES</TITLE>
                        <EXT-REQT>With the approval of the Coordinator, the Dean of Arts, and the relevant Department, a student
                            may credit three hours of Directed Studies in any subject linked to Acadian Studies towards the
                            Minor</EXT-REQT>. </P>
                </PROGRAM>
            </PROGRAMS>
        </DEPARTMENT>
    </FACULTY>
</CALENDAR>
